Ruth Jabrahine Mendez Velazquez

Q C/ Arabia, #11c, Arrollo Hondo, Santo Domingo Distrito Nacional R.D
☐ https://www.linkedin.com/in/ruth-mendez-13515b189/

SUMMARY

Multi-tasking bilingual (English and Spanish) Recruiter with +5 years of experience in the field. Successful in system administration and database. Achieved 76% of massive recruiting over the past years. Adept at accomplishing multiple tasks simultaneously, goal oriented and working effectively under pressure.

SKILL

Proficient in Microsoft office

People Skills

Teamwork skills

Leadership

Problem Solving

EXPERIENCE

2018 - 2020

ERC INTERNATIONAL

RECRUTER

- Develop and execute recruiting plans.
- Perform job and task analysis to document job requirements and objectives.
- Source and recruit candidates by using databases, social media etc.
- Screen applicants to evaluate if they meet the position requirements, conduct interviews using various reliable recruiting and selection tools/methods to filter candidates within schedule.
- Provide analytical and well documented recruiting reports to the rest of the team.
- Promote and sale the company's reputation as "best place to work".
- Conduct regular follow-up with managers to determine the effectiveness of recruiting plans and implementation.

2016 - 2018

Scotiabank

Fraud Analyst

- Monitor real time and identify high risk transactions within the business portfolio.
- Observe customer transactions to identify fraudulent activity such as account take over, theft and similar other risks.
- Resolve queued transactions within the service level agreements to reduce potential revenue losses.
- Interact with the customers to validate information and to confirm or cancel authorizations.
- Monitor constantly customer and transactional records to identify unauthorized transactions and fraudulent accounts.
- Ensure confidentiality of all information collected during investigation.
- Determine existing fraud trends by analyzing accounts and transaction patterns.
- Identify system improvements to prevent fraudulent activities.
- Generate suspicious activity reports and risk management reports for Managers.

EDUCATION

Middle School 2008 - 2012 Christian Faith Primary and Secondary School Antigua And Barbuda Bussines Administration 2017 – Currently enroll Universidad del Caribe Dominican Republic